Many times people purchase life insurance policies
and due to some emergency
they are unable to pay the remaining premiums. Suppose they
pay one premium and go to cancel the policy,
they do
not get the full amount, not even a single rupee. If they
surrender in the first year, even in the second or third
year, they hardly get back the
money for the premium paid.
Keeping this in mind,
ICICI Prudential Life Insurance has
launched a retirement plan, Guaranteed
Pension Plan Flexi with Benefit Enhancement,
where you can surrender your policy at any time and
you will get 100% of your money back,
not even a single rupee will be
deducted. This is an excellent retirement plan, which at
present, till 2024, none of the 24 life insurance companies has
such a retirement
pension plan available, where the customer gets
100% refund on surrendering the policy in the first year.
Hello friends,
my name is Anil Rajput. I am the founder of
Emily First Financial Services, MBA
Finance and have been
working in the corporate sector for 13 years.  I have been and today I am
presenting before you the
GPP
Flexi Benefit Enhancer Plan of ICICI Preference Life Insurance. Let's watch the
video and understand this plan
and if you like the video then
watch mine. Now the option of GPP Flexi Benefit
Enhancer given by the
company has been launched on 18th January 2024.
They have GPP Flex for a long time.
I have made a separate video in full details about it,
you can watch it
on my channel. I will also provide you the link of it at the end.
You will get the link of it in the last 15 seconds of the video.
So now let's see,
in comparison to this type of product,
people in India like to get FD done, they
like fixed deposits, like for example,
here you will see the option given in trillions.
People invest in billions of rupees
in FD. If you
look at Maharashtra, then there is an investment of 25.1 trillion
rupees
under FD. Similarly,
you can see the details of Delhi, Karnataka, Tamil Nadu etc. now.
What happens in a deposit is that you have
a financial instrument, FD
is a financial instrument, anyway there is a
form of GPP or GPP Flexi which
is a financial instrument for you,
but now see, fixed deposit also
gives a guaranteed fixed return and interest,
so GP Flex is also
providing you a guaranteed fixed rate of interest,
but what is the difference between the two,
that is, FD is for a fixed time
only, like if you get an FD for 5 years, 10 years or
more or suppose you want to get an
FD for whole life, then
you cannot do it, but you can
take GPB Flexi for unlimited time,
you can get the benefit for whole life,
secondly, in FD you have the
risk of reinvestment, whether today
your FD rate is at 6.5 or 7,
what will happen next year, what will happen after two years,
you do not know, but in this plan
you have zero reinvestment risk
because once you purchase the policy,
its interest rate  It will be locked forever.
Now let us see what has been the trend of the
savings rate and interest rate in the last 30 years.
Like, if you see in 1992, the
deposit rate was at 12, then
gradually it became 10, then 9, then 8, then 535
but a little bigger, but even now if you
see, it is only at 6.65, so from 12
this decreasing trend had come below 6 and is
moving around 6, right now it is gradually going
down. If you see, in every 10
years the interest rate in India goes
down by 3, like in 1989 it
was at 16, after 10 years it became 13, in
2009 it became 10, in 2019 it became 6
and you can guess what will happen in 2029 and what will happen in the future,
it will keep
reducing further,
but what is there for you in this plan,
you can lock the NT rate today itself,
that too will come  For generations up to the next generation,
like one of its best things is that there is
100% guaranteed money back any time. There are
many NT pension plans in 24 life insurance company
but this is the
only plan in the industry in which you will
get 100% money back on surrender in the first year itself. You
can surrender this policy at any time and
you will not incur any loss.
In this plan, you can also take spouse cover.
You can also take joint life cover and avail
benefit for spouse.
Plus there is also an option of waiver of premium.
Now if we see
this news has also come in Times of India. This company has
advertised it in Times of India
also on 18th.
What happens in retirement planning initially is that first there is amat phase, at
that time you save, at that time you
keep the money, like you keep it in FD,
keep it in PPF, keep it
in other life insurance products, keep it in NPS,
keep it in mutual funds,
after that you come in income phase and you get income,
but is there any such plan which gives
you life insurance  Can it provide time guaranteed income? Can
FD be done? Will
PPF last for 100 years?
Will endum plans of life insurance work? Will
NPS last for 100 years? Can mutual
funds give you guaranteed income for 100 years?
But this plan will give you guaranteed income for 100 years
and is also flexible;
you can withdraw 100% of the money whenever you need it. Now let us
understand with an example. Hari is a 50 year old
person. His wife is Supriya whose
age is 45 years and they are purchasing an NT policy in joint life,
ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance's GPP
Flexi
Enhancer. Here they are saving ₹1 lakh and
putting it in this plan for the next 10 years. So, the
acumen phase which is from 50 to 60 years,
where they deposit the money,
they are depositing the money in that phase and
assume that the second person, that is,
whoever is the second person will survive last.  If
he dies at the age of 90, then
after completion of 6 years, when after 10 years of premium
increase, he will start getting an income of Rs. 00 in joint life
and whenever the last
member dies, then whatever deposited
money i.e. Rs. 1 crore will be
returned to whoever his nominee is.
Now let us see, but in case of
emergency, if there is any
need of money before retirement, for
example, you see that Hari had a
heart attack on the second year and
now he needs money at home, then
what did he do, he withdrew the entire money,
he got 100% money back,
he closed the policy and withdrew the entire money, there was
no loss of even a single rupee, whereas till
today, till 18th January
2024, whatever NT plan you take from whichever company, if you
close the first year,
you do not get even a single rupee,
but now you
see here, there is a trend, like you will see
that if you go to surrender in the first year, you get Rs. 20-30, in the
second year, you see the trend here  You must be
understanding that to get 100%
surrender benefit till the age of 100, you have to
wait for 10 years, only then your surrender
value becomes 100%, but in this plan
you see there is a straight line, be it the first year,
second year, third year or fourth year,
you will get 100% surrender value, so this is
its major and best feature, it
is an excellent option in this policy, it is
clearly told here that no questions will be
asked from you, you will get 100% surrender
value from the first year itself,
now let us understand with an example, the plan is
Guaranteed Pension Plan, not Flexi Enhancer, but
Flexi Plan which is available now,
I repeat again, the detailed video of this plan,
GPP Pension Plan Flexi
is available on my channel,
its link is available in the last 15 seconds of this video of mine,
you can watch the entire video there,
so purchase this Flex policy, the
customer's age is 50 years, the
premium for 10 years is defunct  The period is of 10 years, that is, after
completion of 10 years, he will
start getting income. He is taking single life with
return of premium option, he has
taken the option of GIT, he will get pension of
₹76000, he is paying a premium of ₹1 lakh. Now, the
old plan which is GP
Flexi, now if you look here, in the first year
you will see the surrender value as zero.
Notice that in this plan also there is
surrender value. In the second year you pay 10 lakh
and also a total of 20 lakh, then
your surrender value becomes 9900.
But
what will be the benefit for you in Benefit Enhancer GP Flex Benefit Enhancer, for example, a
40 year old person is purchasing the policy and
paying 10 years premium for 5 years.
Now you see, in the first year itself the surrender
benefit is 10 lakh and in the second year it is
20 lakh, so you are getting back 100% of the money paid in it.  At the
same time, as soon as
your special surplus increases,
your surrender value will also increase. So
this is how this option works.
Now see, GPP Flux Enhanced Waiver of
Premium Benefit Waiver of Premium means that
if there is death, then the premium payment will be waived.
Now for example, Hari
reached Hari in the second year, that is, she died,
so what will happen now is that the
remaining eight premiums will be
paid by ICICI Prudential and the income that was supposed to come to his
wife Supriya ji for 11 years will continue to
come and if we
assume at the age of 90, Supriya ji
also dies, then the NT will
get back all the remaining purchase price money.
Now see, here I will try to tell you
how many premiums were paid. Hari Bhai
paid only two premiums.
Who paid the remaining eight premiums? ICICI Prudential
means a total of Rs 1 crore was paid.
Two premiums were paid by Hari Hari Bhai and the remaining
eight premiums were paid by ICICI.  Filled it, that means
you have paid ₹ crore and Supriya ji was
getting income every year and 100% of her
money, that is, the entire 1 crore, will go to
her nominee on Supriya ji's death.
Now see, the custom
paid a premium of ₹ 730000 in two years.
She got an income of ₹ 90 lakh till the age of 90. As long as Supriya ji was
alive, she got an income, so
multiply 730000 into it for 30 years, then
you got a huge amount,
plus you got back ₹ 1 crore,
which was your entire purchase price.
So, in this way, you see, this is an
excellent plan provided to you by the company
which will provide you pension for life, will
provide you guaranteed pension, will provide you
liquidity, we are giving you
interest rates today. The interest rates will be fixed in 2024
even though the saving rates, as you have
seen, have been going down since 92, are going
down every 10 years.  But your
rates will never go down.
You will get the option of waiver of premium in this policy. You will
get the option of joint life in it.
So this is an excellent plan which will help you in your
financial planning and retirement
planning. If you liked the video, then
definitely subscribe to my YouTube4FFFS. There are already
more than 300 videos there
which will help you in your financial planning.
Thank you so
much.